Researchers grew tiny human brains from
stem cells, embodied them in Pac-Man,
and continuously shocked them until they
did something right. They wanted to
demonstrate that you can train brain
organoids by giving them the reward of
silence in a hellscape. They also wanted
to demonstrate both long-term and
short-term memory, of which the brain
organoids seem to have both. They worked
over some of the lobe brain ideas. So
they grew two separate brain organoids,
connected them through axons, this is
like a spinal cord of sorts, and gave
each one a different job in Pac-Man.
That actually is really cool. This
builds on some previous research where
people are trying to get brain organized
to operate robots better by having a
loed brain. Kind of like how one side of
your body operates your left arm and the
other one operates your right arm. It it
works in robots, too. They set up these
little Pac-Man inspired mazes. And
literally, they use Pac-Man for their
pictures. In these mazes, we have our
brain organoids that are operating this
little bee here. And they can move
around and get food. They're given
constant unpleasant stimulation. And
when they get food, they finally get a
break from it. This is kind of different
than what we've seen with other brain
organoid training in which they're given
dopamine as a reward or ordered signals.
In this case, they just get constant
electric shocks. And when they acquire
food, they finally get a break. And not
all of the brain organoids even had the
opportunity for a reward. And some of
them were given more severe punishments
for being caught by the cat or the
Pac-Man ghost. This operated in a closed
loop learning system. So a computer
would give electrical current and
stimulate the brain organoids, which
they do not enjoy in this case. The
brain organoids react to that stimuli.
It's recorded on an external hard drive
and then that is analyzed and sent back
to the computer and then continues to
shock the brain organoids. What they
found is that they are capable of both
long-term and short-term memory. If they
give them continuous punishment,
especially severe punishment, they
perform better. But if they stop giving
them any punishment, they start to
forget how to play the game pretty
quickly. You can see that each one gets
control of the body in some way. One of
them has left and right activity, the
other one has down and up activity. They
learn to work together or suffer. I'm
not entirely sure why this particular
study bothered me so much because
usually when I read about the brain
organoids, they're given a reward, not
punishment. And the reward is less
punishment. It's kind of reminding me of
my childhood, to be honest. I'm kidding.
In terms of keeping these guys alive and
making them bigger, there's been a lot
of progress. I've seen some research
giving them tiny heart organoids. So, it
seems the issue with the core becoming
hypoxic is less of an issue. And I've
seen some papers keeping them alive for
over 300 days. They are also learning
with AI. I've seen some pretty weird
ones lately. So, we've had companies
like Cortical Labs and Final Spark
release neuroplatforms which people can
utilize brain organoid computing from a
distance and those papers are just
starting to come out. Like these guys,
they taught brain organoids how to read
braille. Turns out when you have a
single brain organoid, they can read
braille to about 61% accuracy. But if
you have multiples, at least three, they
go up to 83%. This is considered
important because brain organoids use a
lot less energy in terms of just wattage
versus using other forms of computation.
They are better at some things like
utilizing a body, doing nonlinear
thought. A lot of video games, too. That
was found with Pong. Yes, researchers
keep putting brain organoids in game
world and it's it's getting a little
weird. Join me next time as I keep you
up to date on unspeakable horrors. And
I'm only partly kidding. I do think the
brain organoids are really neat. It's
just something about this study bothered